http://isaacjordan.me http://uk.linkedin.com/in/ijordan http://github.com/sheepzez

Objective

Third year undergraduate student at the University of Glasgow with 1 year of professional experience in software engineering. Experienced in a variety of languages and technology stacks. Seeking an internship placement for the summer of 2016.

Education

University of Glasgow

Glasgow, UK

Master of Science in Computer Science

Sep. 2013 - 2018

- Studied Maths and Comp Sci in Second Year, and Maths, Physics, and Comp Sci in First Year.
- Strong A grades in all Computer Science classes, and many Mathematics classes.
- First Prize at Glasgow Uni Tech Society Hackathon 2015 (see projects)

Trinity Academy

Edinburgh, UK

Secondary School

2007 - 2013

Sixth Year: Adv. Higher Computing (A), Adv. Higher Mathematics (A), Adv. Higher Physics (B)

Fifth Year: Higher Computing (A), Higher Mathematics (A), Higher Physics (A), Higher Chemistry (A), Higher Modern Studies (B)

Work Experience

TBR Global Chauffeuring

Glasgow, UK

Software Developer (Part-Time)

September 2015 - Present

- Working on automated processing system for customer's itineraries using C#.

TBR Global Chauffeuring

Glasgow, UK

Software Developer Intern

Jun 2015 - Sep 2015

- Created a toolset to improve how easily customer information could be obtained from Emirates
 Airline. Toolset consisted of a reader to obtain XML files from an FTP server in Dubai, the reader
 had to be robust and reliable so that data could be relied upon.
- The next step was a parser to extract the flight manifests from the Passenger Name Records (PNR) stored in an XML file. This also validated all addresses using external services (OpenAddressesUK, Google Maps) and marked any suspicious data with warnings.
- The final step was a management web app that allowed multiple users to simulatenously inspect, manipulate, and import the data into the TBR Global main system using a REST API.
- Played a major role in creating a microsite for Visa call-centers to use to quickly create new
 international jobs in the TBR Global system. Worked as part of a team of 5 to complete the project
 in a very tight deadline.
- Also created a tool to validate all timezone information stored in the TBR Global database using Google Maps Timezone API.
- Heavily used C#, MVC 5, EntityFramework, SQL, JavaScript, jQuery, and Bootstrap.

Chi Squared Innovations

Remote

Software Developer (Part-Time)

Sep 2014 - Jun 2015

- Worked closely with CEO to recreate the public facing website in-house using the Python/Django webstack.
- Used D3.js, a JavaScript data visualisation library to create several dynamic graphs.

Projects

GUTS Hackathon 2015

https://github.com/Sheepzez/yorkhill-kinect

Kinect game for Yorkhill Children's Hospital

Oct 2015

- Winner of first prize overall, and Morgan Stanley's challenge at Glasgow University Tech Society (GUTS) Hackathon.
- Game using Windows XNA in which players can work together to scrub a hospital of germs.
 Controlled by MS Kinect 2.0.
- Utilises C# Tasks for parallel processing of Kinect's multiple data streams.
- Created in 3 days with a team of three.

Google Maps API .NET

https://github.com/ericnewton76/gmaps-api-net

Google Maps API C# Library

Jun 2015 - Present

- Major contributor to open source class library.
- Personally implemented Places API, and TimeZone API in the library.
- Help manage tickets created by users, and decide how issues are tackled.

Grub Grabber

https://github.com/Sheepzez/GrubGrabber

Web app to help my friends decide where to go for lunch

Jan 2015 - Mar 2015

- Developed as part of University course.
- Utilises Python/Django webstack, Google Maps JS API, and jQuery.
- http://grubgrabber.pythonanywhere.com/

The Matrixonator

https://github.com/Sheepzez/Matrixonator-Java

JavaFX application for manipulating matrices

Dec 2014 - Mar 2015

- Originally a Python project, this open source Java port proved to be much more powerful
- Allows users to manipulate matrices via a GUI.
- Handles basic operations such as addition, subtraction, and multiplication as well as more complex ones such as eigenvalue and reduced row-echeclon form (RREF) calculation.
- Can identify shortcuts for calculations, such as eigenvalue calculation for matrices in RREF.
- Has extensive unit tests, and utilises a continuous integration server to test commits and pull requests.

Skills

Languages: C#, Java, Python, JavaScript, SQL, C

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Foundation, Django, jQuery, EntityFramework 6, IIS, C# LINQ

Tools: Visual Studio 2013/2015, SQL Server Management Studio, Eclipse, Git, SVN, Mercurial

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux (Debian, Fedora)

Miscellaneous: Exceptional troubleshooting and debugging skills. Able to quickly grasp interactions in large projects. Strong algorithmic skills.